Guide to the Henri R. Ferger papers, 1920-1940.
Ferger, Henri R. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Henri R. Ferger papers, 1920-1940.
6646
Ferger, Henri R.(Henri Rabb),
11 cubic ft.
Correspondence, movie film, photographs, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, diaries, published materials, and visual materials documenting the career of the Reverend Henri R. Ferger.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, diaries, published materials, and visual materials documenting the career of the Reverend Henri R. Ferger as a missionary and educator with the Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions in India. Includes photographs, 35mm slides, lantern slides, stereo slides, and 16mm films related to Ferger's work in India and travel to many other countries.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ferger, Henri R. b. 1889.; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Board of Foreign Missions.
Subjects:
Missionaries -- India.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Documents
Subseries Ia. Correspondence
Subseries Ib. Other
Series II. Visual Materials
Subseries IIa. 35mm Slides
Subseries IIb. Lantern Slides
Subseries IIc. Stereo Slides
Subseries IId. Photographs
Subseries IIe. 16mm Film
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Documents
  - Subseries Ia. Correspondence
    - Audio Visual "In Retrospect", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carl Nelson to John Ferger regarding Henri Ferger, May 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1934-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and friends, 1949-1959, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - General, 1929-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General, on old age, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters home (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters home, 1915-1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters home, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters home, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letters home, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters home, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters home, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters home, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters home, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Letters home, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Letters home, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Letters home, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters home, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letters home, 1941 or 1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letters home, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Letters home, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Letters home, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Letters home, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Letters home, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letters home, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Letters home, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Letters home, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Letters home, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Letters home, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Letters home, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Letters home, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Letters home, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Letters home, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Letters home, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Letters home, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Letters home, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Letters home, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Letters home, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Letters home, en route to America, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Letters home, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Letters home, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Letters home, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Letters home, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Kaisar-i-Hind silver medal, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Kashmir, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Scouting, 1960, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Subseries Ib. Documents
    - Personal labor reports, 1925-1954 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Publications with pictures by Ferger (Box 1, Folder 58-61)
    - Reports, 1938, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Henri and Kathryn Ferger passports, 1956, 1968, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Henri and Kathryn Ferger passports, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia Presbyterian Historical Society files (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Birth of Twin Nations pamphlet by Carl Taylor, December 18, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Barkpur Primary School workbooks, in Urdu, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The "Dyb-Dob" unbound, published by the students in Dehra Dun, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The "Dyb-Dob" bound, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Self appraisal of the Four Square Life (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Copies of articles by Ferger (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Publicity releases, Presbyterian Church, 1943-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - The Puzzle Ring of India (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Indian meal: Recipes and preparation for groups, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Social Survey, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - First Aid Certificates, 1919, 1935, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Henry Wilson letters and articles, 1938-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Farrukhabad Christian High School, 1939-1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dehra Dun, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Indian Christian art. Includes Christmas cards and two original watercolors (Topno). (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Christian art in India pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Saints of India Series: Pandita Ramaboi. Founded by Ferger (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Flight over Latin America, by Ferger, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Sermons (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
    - Clippings, notes, copies of letters sent to JC Kalleen, 1910-1913 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Journal of Ferger's cycle trip from NJ to Ohio, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Financial records: Account books until close of college Rawalpindi, 1910-1914 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Financial records: 2 account books, 1937-1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Passports, 1910-1931 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - International certificates of vaccination (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Chattanooga Times diary, 1893-1894 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Farewell tributes on leaving Fatehgarh, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 25 publicity pamphlets edited by Ferger (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Farewells to HR Ferger (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - A Sari for Sita, by Nina Millen with photographs by Ferger, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Games (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Audio Visual production of the Transformation of Life, including scripts, paper dolls mounted on cloth, flannel backdrops, and slides (Box 3)
    - Diaries, 1910-1967 (Box 4)
    - Book of poems collected by Henri Ferger (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - The Union Jack: It's History and Description (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Scout history in India (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Programs from Scout Masters' Training course, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Record book of Scout troop Dehra Dun, 1918-1919 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Two journals by Henri Ferger (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Dehra Dun boy scout troop (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Publications (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Certificates from USA and India boy scouts associations (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Bharat Scouts- certificates including award of Silver Elephant (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Ferger's notes on training course, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - General- early opposition to Indian boy scout troop formation by the British, 1916-1922 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Woodstock- Ferger's first scout troop in an international school (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Lahore attempt to form a scout troop, 1916 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings and matted images (Box 28)
    - Alarm clock watch (Box 28)
- Series II. Visual Materials
  - Subseries IIa. 35mm Slides
    - Lisbon and Malta, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Korea (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - India (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Afghanistan, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - South America, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Turkey and Greece, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Christian church and mission work: India (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - South America, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - India and Allahabad, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - India, Nepal, Ceylon, Kashmir (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Dryden and personal (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - India and Nepal (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Senior Citizen Housing Project (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Pakistan, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Kenya, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Greece, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Hong Kong, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Nepal, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Hawaii, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Japan (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Ethiopia, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Spain, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Egypt and Sudan, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Taiwan, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Indonesia (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Morocco, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Turkey, Cyprus and Greece, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Guatemala, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - USSR, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Alaska, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - USA trip west, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - South America, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Caribbean, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - England and Scotland, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Panchita, Chichicastenango, India (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - India (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - India: places (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - India: people (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Konyak Nagas, India refugees (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Sauras, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Garo, Assam, Angami, Tankhul, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Allahabad: places (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Latin America (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - West Africa and Cameroon, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Nigeria, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - West Africa, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Africa, ca. 1977 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Africa, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 20-22)
    - USSR, 91972 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - India, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Nepal, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Allahabad and Fatehgarh (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - India mission work, churches (Box 25, Folder 27-28)
    - India, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 29-30)
    - AVA India (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - India medical (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Colored slides (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - India, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Maps of India, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Thailand, Cambodia, Taiwan, Burma, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 37-41)
    - Iran, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Germany, Holland, Italy, Switzerland, Denmark, Egypt, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Nova Scotia, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Bermuda, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - World's Fair, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Ceylon, Fiji, Tahiti, New Zealand, Singapore, Malaya, Australia, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 47-49)
    - Non-religious Indian paintings (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Religious Indian paintings (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - USA west coast, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Cloth flag with spinning wheel (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Map of India with regions and customs (Folder 1)
  - Subseries IIb. Lantern Slides
    - Glass slides A 1/3-32/2, 1916-1920 (Box 20)
    - India and Pakistan (Box 21)
    - Lantern slides (Box 22)
  - Subseries IIc. Stereo slides
    - Plastic stereo slides from India, Kashmir, Thailand, and Alaska. Includes 2 viewers. (Box 29)
  - Subseries IId. Photographs
    - Color enlargements: Washington Monument, Temple Emerald Buddha, Wellesley, Brooklyn Botanical Gardens, Niagara (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Kashmir color enlargements (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Manali color enlargements (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Color enlargements: Assam plains, Garos, Abors, Asmagas (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Konyak Nagas, Tankhul, Angami color enlargements (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - USA, Canada color enlargements (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kashmir, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Guatemala, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Ethiopia (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Nigeria,, Ghana, Senegal, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Glossy prints of disposed negatives (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Zujipan, Kashmir, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Good Samaritan color enlargements, ca. 1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Prodigal Son (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Transformed Life color enlargements, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - European Trip enlargements, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Photograph album, 1914-1928 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Konyak: for film strip (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - South India (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - AVA enlargements, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Japan AVA conference, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Nepal enlargements not in film strip (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Fatehgarh training course, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Heart of India-Drama (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - AVA training course, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Transformed Life (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - AVA second selections (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - AVA work enlargements, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - NCC Guntur, Allahabad, 1953, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Calcutta general assembly, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Lushai Hills not in filmstrip, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Integration of Muslims with church, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Assam work camp, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Allahabad work camp, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Fatehgarh mission hospital, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Luck Now Meeting WCC (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Stone Screens, India (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Scout photographs (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
    - Jhansi Scouts, 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Korea, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Burma, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Cambodia, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Thailand (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Philippines (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Japan, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Refugees, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Jumnotic prints, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Kasmir, 1910-1913 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Puppet making (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - West India hospital (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - NCC Guntur, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - NCC Allahabad (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Pictures of children (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Kashmir (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Panjab Training Course (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Kasganj, Taj Mahal, Fatahpur Sihri, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous personal, Isabella Thoburn (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Camp Tadescong, Sari for Sita (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Kinnaid College, Indian Notables, ECC (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Jabalpur, Allahabad Leper Asylum, Landow AVA, miscellaneous scouts (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Caste Markes, Taj Mahal, group with Rajindra Prasad (1951), Woodstock group (1940), Wawayanda (1914-1915) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Chiengmai, Allahabad (1965), Dehra Dun Scouts (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - North India Mission samples (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Pokwo and Ethiopia (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Philippines (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Burma set for large albums (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Thailand set for large album, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Korea set for album (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - John Beal, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Japan set for album (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Moga, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ludhiana School, Kashmir, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Woodstock Scouts, 1917, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Dehra Dun Scouts, 1918-1920 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - India: personal, 1915-1924 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Rawalpindi: personal, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - FC College Lahure, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Camp Kline, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Camp Glen Gray, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Camp Cowaw, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Camp Morris, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Dryden set for master book (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - USA Personal, 1915, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Jabalpur AVA Prints (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Dhantari, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Thailand, china, Japan, Manila, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - China set for album (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Scout cards (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Loose miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Pindi and Kashmir, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 3-5)
    - Mattu hospital, Ethiopia, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Ethiopia, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Family (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - China set for album (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - India, 1910-1919 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Transformed Life (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
    - Thailand, China, Manila, Japan, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 15-18)
    - Ankur Wat (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Photographs 1-899, with negatives (Box 10)
    - Photographs 900-1399, with negatives (Box 10)
    - Photographs 1400-1799, with negatives (Box 10)
    - Photographs 1800-2259, with negatives (Box 10)
    - Photographs 2260-2949, with negatives (Box 11)
    - Photographs 2950-3679, with negatives (Box 11)
    - Photographs 3680-4320, with negatives (Box 11)
    - Photographs 4320-4949, with negatives (Box 11)
    - Photographs 4950-5558, with negatives (Box 12)
    - Photographs 5850-6523, with negatives (Box 12)
    - Photographs P1-P5, with negatives and guide, 1936-1941 (Box 12)
    - Photographs A, D1, G1, P5, P6. With negatives (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous photographs with negatives and indexes, 1945-1946, undated (Box 13)
    - Prints glued to labelled index cards, 1911-1916 (Box 14)
    - Prints and negatives, some from films, 1916, 1917, 1924 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, chiefly India (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Christ of the Andes (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Baphur hostel school (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Scouts: Dehra Dun, Ludhirna,Jhansi (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous prints, ca. 1930s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - China, Japan, Korea, Philippines, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Photograph guides and descriptions (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Photograph descriptions for removed negatives (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 6 negative books (Box 23)
    - Pilgrims from Turkestan to Mecca (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Muslim at Prayer (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Book Store, Lahure (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Girls at village wall (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Reel thread, Travancure (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Taj Mahal, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Himalayas from China Peak (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Woman, Buxar, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Indian Madonna (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Christian boy (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Kashmiri woman, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Sheesh Nag, goats with shepherds (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Pandita Ramabai (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Jhansi (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Girl in burqa, Lahure (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Camel cart (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Kashmiri man (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Kulu valley (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - 'Transformed Life' (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Bazaar in Mortakka (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Snake charmer (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Kashmiri man and girl (Box 24, Folder 22-23)
    - Boy near Ujjain (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Luchnow Gate (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Mar Canal (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Shepherd (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - India (Box 24, Folder 28-31)
    - South America (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Farrukhabad high school (Box 24, Folder 33-34)
    - Miscellaneous enlargements (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Missions, Panjab, miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Extra mission (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Lahore (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Jhansi (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Kashmir, Ludhiana scouts (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Jhansi, miscellaneous India (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous India and photograph album (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Prints with negatives 5560-5890, miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Mrs. Moore village medical (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - India Village Service (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Memorial hospital, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Kamalganj, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - High school, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - School and hostel, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Sari for Sita- Albert Sherry (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Sari for Sita (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Moga Feh, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - ABU duplicates (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Transformed Life (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Allahabad (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - China and Japan (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Christmas, 1944 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Christmas, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Calcutta refugees, Christmas, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Tibetan patient and daughter (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Cal Hazlett (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Magan Chula (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Monsoon clouds, Allahabad (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Dehra Dun, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - John to Pindari (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Chile, Colombia, Brazil, Guatemala, Yucatan (Box 27, Folder 23-30)
    - Villages (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Pindari hike, Farrukhabad scouts (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Jamil Khan, Allahabad (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Hinduism, set 3 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Women, set 6 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Bazaar life, set 7 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Indian life, set 8 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Kashmir village life, set 10 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Men, set 14 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Mussoorie and Landour, set 17 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Beggars, set 18 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Transportation, set 20 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Kashmir Mountains, set 27 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Indian Life 2, set 28 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Mission work, set 30 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Mission work, set 32 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Mission work, set 35 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Mission work, lepers, set 37 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Delhi and Agra, set 39 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Kumbh Mela, Allahabad, set 40, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
    - Photograph albums- Mission work (Box 30-31)
    - Photograph album- miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - Photograph album- places, missionaries and others (Box 33)
    - Photograph album- most popular pictures, people (Box 34)
  - Subseries IIe. 16mm Films
    - Film list and descriptions (Box 19)
    - Travancore, 1945; F-391 (Box 17)
    - Call of the Mountains, F-392 (Box 17)
    - Prodigal Son, F-393 (Box 17)
    - Kashmir, F-394 (Box 17)
    - The Village and I, F-395 (Box 17)
    - Story of Zacchaeus, F-396 (Box 17)
    - Good Samaritan, 1948; F-397 (Box 17)
    - Nagpur NCC meeting, 1950; F-398 (Box 17)
    - Photography by HR Ferger, F-399 (Box 17)
    - None too Good, Bombay trees, Amaltar blossoms, 1961; F-400 (Box 17)
    - Dedication near Shihohabad, 1950; F-401 (Box 17)
    - Garden, 1936; F-402 (Box 17)
    - Peach blossoms, Scout, 1952; F-403 (Box 17)
    - Boats on River, Allahabad, 1950; F-404 (Box 17)
    - Library, Hostel, Corner of Church, 1935; F-405 (Box 17)
    - Boys' movement, Buffalo, F-406 (Box 17)
    - Khaliq titles, F-407 (Box 17)
    - Dedication near Shihohabad, first reel, 1950; F-408 (Box 17)
    - Good Samaritan extras, 1947; F-409 (Box 17)
    - Caldwell Smith, F-410 (Box 17)
    - Dehra Dun, F-411 (Box 17)
    - Ludhiana, F-412 (Box 17)
    - FC College, F-413 (Box 17)
    - Ludhiana school and hospital, F-414 (Box 17)
    - Father's World, F-415 (Box 17)
    - Sunset, F-416 (Box 17)
    - Kinnaird, F-417 (Box 17)
    - Maharajahs, F-418 (Box 17)
    - Cuts from film, F-419 (Box 17)
    - The Philippines, F-420 (Box 17)
    - Moga, F-421 (Box 17)
    - Rang Mahur school, F-422 (Box 17)
    - Taj Mahal, F-423 (Box 17)